<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kirsten Hilling</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kirsten Hilling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Choose Sides? The Power of R and Python</title>
      <link>/post/2021/05/06/welcome-to-kirsten-hilling-s-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/05/06/welcome-to-kirsten-hilling-s-website/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be a constant battle of “R” people and “Python” people. Which is better? What is more practical? Which is cooler? To be honest, they’re both great, but in their own ways. And at the end of the day, just knowing one will severely close you off from the pros of both. R has many pre-installed packages that let users do an endless amount of actions. From data visualization, generating statstics, and much more, using R’s packages makes things a lot more simplified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>The dataset I am using in this project pertains to various social factors and health insurance charges. Specifically, it looks at age, sex, bmi, number of children, whether or not they are a smoker, region they live in the US, and their yearly charges through health insurance. There are 7 variables total and 1338 observations. I am interested to see whether or not there is an interaction between all of these factors and how much individuals pay for their health insurance charges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project1</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>knitr::opts_chunk$set(echo = TRUE, eval = TRUE, fig.align = &amp;quot;center&amp;quot;, warning = F, message = F, tidy=TRUE, tidy.opts=list(width.cutoff=60), R.options=list(max.print=100)) In this project, I am going to be using the World Happiness Report data from 2016 and a Happiness and Alcohol Consumption dataset from 2016. The first data set contains the rankings and scores from the World Happiness Report which measures the average happiness in each country based on several factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
